Matthew Botschner

Data Analyst Apprentice

(941) 246-9975 | matt.botschner@gmail.com | LinkedIn | github

PROFILE

Hard working problem solver with several years of leadership experience. I enrolled in Nashville Software School in order to gain the skills necessary for a total career pivot into a field that is more sustainable and growth oriented. I am very analytical, logical and have an actively inquiring mind.

SKILLS

- Git/GitHub
- Excel
- SQL (PostgreSQL)
- Python
- Tableau
- Power BI

Leadership and Management

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

July 2022 - Present

Data Analyst Apprentice

Intensive full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using *matplotlib* and *seaborn*
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

PROJECTS

- City Cemetery Burials (Excel): Cleaned and analyzed data on burials at the Nashville City Cemetery to provide marketing materials for future advertisements. City Cemetery
- Data Analyst Jobs (PostgreSQL): Analyzed data based on current jobs in the data field to provide a clearer picture of what was available in the market. Analyst jobs
- Bigfoot Dashboard(Tableau): Dashboard about bigfoot sightings to show off visualizations. Bigfoot

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Production Manager | Nicoletto's Pasta Company | 11/2020 - Present

Responsible for overall production of all pasta, both fresh and dried; training new hires, and overall brand ambassadorship.

- Supported and refined in house best-practices relating to production
- Initiated data driven metrics relating to waste/efficiency, started logging and weighing all product thrown away and updated par levels accordingly to minimize loss.

Landscape Architect | Forever Green Plant Care | 05/2018 - 10/2020

Responsible for the maintenance and appearance of flower-beds, trees, and hedges in a variety of customer settings.

Self-motivated with little to no oversight to complete jobs quickly and efficiently

EDUCATION

